Kyle Bowen

kyle.m.bowen@gmail.com 909-344-9100 Ogden, UT

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

https://github.com/kylebowen https://www.linkedin.com/in/kyle-m-bowen Portfolio Site: https://kylebowen.github.io

Professional Profile

Full stack developer with ten years of experience in the media industry as both a creative freelancer (clients included Coke, Cinemark, & Ragnar Relays) and a full-time analyst for Tribune Publishing (managing video distribution for multiple sites including the Los Angeles Times & Chicago Tribune). Willing and excited to learn additional technologies to contribute to a development team. Additional experience includes obsessive cycling, semi-professional beatboxing, and way too much time watching Sandi Metz talks.

Technical Skills

Programming/Web: JavaScript(ES6), React(16), Redux(4), jQuery, Socket.IO, Git/GitHub, HTML5, CSS3, Node.js(10), Mocha, Jest, REST APIs, Ruby, Ruby on Rails.

Software: Tableau, MS Office, Cubase, ProTools, Photoshop, Lightroom, Premiere Pro

Database/DBMS: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redshift

Recent Projects

What's the Story: A real-time collaborative multiplayer story-telling game. A cross between Mad Libs & Telephone.

(Tech Stack: React, Redux, Socket.IO, Express, Node, Mongo)

Privet: Learn Russian based on a spaced-repetition algorithm. (Tech Stack: React, Redux, Express, Node, Mongo)

ShaveReducer: An app for tracking personal inventory and shave history for wet-shaving enthusiasts.

(Tech Stack: React, Redux, Express, Node, Mongo)

Professional Experience

Tribune Publishing Company, Los Angeles, CA - Analyst, Video Distribution

2016 - 2018

- Increased company video views 1,000-fold over 18 months by analyzing performance trends and user behavior in order to drive production and distribution strategy for the central video production team serving the tronc network of news sites (including Los Angeles Times, Chicago Tribune, Baltimore Sun, and more.)
- Created custom dashboards and reports combining Adobe Analytics, Amazon Redshift, and Excel which decreased the weekly time requirement by 50% and improved accuracy by 10%.
- Developed new processes and improvements in team workflow leading to decreased overhead and increased efficiency in planning, cross-team communication, and product distribution.

AutoUplinkUSA of SoCal, Los Angeles, CA - Independent Automotive Data Agent

2014 – 2016

- Prioritize and effectively allocate time to vehicle photography and data collection across multiple dealers to optimize productivity and ensure timely distribution of 300-500 daily image and data uploads.
- Quickly and accurately catalog vehicle data and options, and prepare vehicle signage to meet DMV requirements while staying abreast of changing regulations.

Self Employed, Los Angeles, CA - Freelance Audio Engineer & Photographer

2008 - 2016

• Audio, Photo, and Video production for national clients including Ragnar Relay Series, Ragnar Trail Relay, Coke, and Cinemark.

Education

THINKFUL - Engineering Immersion

2018

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery,
 Node.js, React, Redux, and algorithms & data structures.
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.

Mt. San Antonio College - Music Performance

2001 - 2004

• Studied Voice and Tuba in internationally acclaimed ensembles. Left before completing degree to pursue work in industry.